NISHTHA RASTOGI

Delhi, 110092 • 9625537337 • Nishtha1111.nr@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I hold an integrated BA + MA degree in Clinical Psychology from Amity University, Noida. My professional journey includes five internships, during which I gained extensive experience through case observations, case history taking, and one-on-one client interactions. Additionally, I have conducted psychological assessments, enhancing my practical skills in clinical settings. My academic contributions include the publication of a research paper titled "Exploring the Relationship Between Adverse Childhood Experiences and Learning Strategies in Students". With experience in both primary and secondary research, I bring a strong foundation in data collection, analysis and interpretation to my work.

RESEARCH PAPER

EXPLORING THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN ADVERSE CHILDHOOD EXPERIENCES AND LEARNING STRATGIES

Conducted primary research, including data collection and analysis, using SPSS (Statistical Package for the Social Sciences). Authored and successfully published the dissertation in International Journal of Interdisciplinary Approaches in Psychology (Psychopedia Journal), November 2024.

Citation: Rastogi, N., & Khanam, A. (2024). Exploring the relationship between Adverse Childhood Experiences and Learning Strategies in Students. *International Journal of Interdisciplinary Approaches in Psychology*, 2(11), 38-54. https://psychopediajournals.com/index.php/ijiap/article/view/589

WORK EXPERIENCE

60 Hours internship, Amar Jyoti Charitable Trust, Karkardooma

Jan 2024 - Feb 2024

I interned in amar jyoti and administered various assessments and was posted in different departments. (CGC, EIP, OT, SPEECH THERAPY ETC). We gave services to people, majorly children with disabilities through a holistic approach. I interacted with the clients took casestudy and administered tests on them.

120 hours internship, Yashoda Hospital, Kaushambi

May 2023 - June 2023

I did my internship under a clinical psychology and 2 psychiatrists. I observed several cases (around 140 cases in total)

Understood case history-taking history and MSE format. Studied about the schools of psychology, depression, anxiety, OCD, ADHD, autism and it's assessment. And studied bipolar disorder, schizophrenia and DID. Observed several cases and took case history and conducted psychological assessment tests on the patients.

90 hours Internship, We Avec U, New Delhi

May 2022 - July 2022

The internship started with an orientation taken by my external guide. I learned about case history, MSE, ethics, and the basics of counselling. I also did a movie analysis and presentations. I also went to juvenile justice and interacted with people there and got to know their cases and took their case histories and also did several activities with them and built rapport.

60 hours internship (HVCO), The Holistic Psyche in collaborationwith AAROHAN Ngo, New Delhi

Dec 2021

My experience in the 60 hours of volunteering with the NGO didn't just teach me that life is not the same for everyone but also made me understand that there is no better way of attaining peace in life

than being helpful to others. The smiles on the faces of the people who benefitted from the drives conducted by us made me feel a different sense of relief.

50 hours internship, The Holistic Psyche, New Delhi

July 2021 - Aug 2021

Rapport formation, Case study taking skills, Mental status examination (MSE), Role play, Discussion on some case studies Psychological Testing and Psychological Assessments

(Standard progressive matrices test, MUSIC test, Vineland social meturity scale VSMS test), IO test on

{Standard progressive matrices test, MUSIC test, Vineland social maturity scale VSMS test), IQ test on a client. Report writing, relaxation therapy, and Test was conducted on the last day.

EDUCATION

Amity University - B.A+ M.A Clinical Psychology Greenfields Public School, Delhi July 2020 - Dec 2024 April 2011 - April 2019

COURSES/ WORKSHOP

• Journal Therapy. The Holistic Psyche July 2021

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1JR7uNdPzvlCDvMP8PjwLokZVs1 n-0EI/view?usp=sharing

- Psychological Trauma and Conflict/Resolution in Present Times 24th Feb, 2022 https://drive.google.com/file/d/1CluE 5n3sL2nwqUgoLqe0mWd7ExthpX/view?usp=sharing
- Transpersonal Development 1st April 2023 https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Jg4sKv3MRTqm8KoGUcctn5-z5cTdJCin/view?usp=sharing
- Cognitive Behaviour Therapy Workshop https://drive.google.com/file/d/1At7VXWzF_quHlhBDEFoxYV9nWpZ5F525/view?usp=sharing
- Trauma Informed Care Workshop https://drive.google.com/file/d/1X8sN2SXhnIOHTxNb--RQFXC0V4hgwoRl/view?usp=sharing
- Abnormal Psychology Workshop https://drive.google.com/file/d/1C4rP2T3z1Lvl00LGO7OcqGvviRkBqrwX/view?usp=sharing

SKILLS

Research

problem solving

Able to Work with Teams, Microsoft Office, Word, Excel, PowerPointEffective Time

Management

Fast Learner

Adaptability Dependable and Responsible

Active Listening Interpersonal Communication Skills